All right. Uh,
a big week
for AI stocks falling. So, let's uh
let's try to go through this. There's a
lot of things I'm going to try to do.
I'm not going to spend as much time uh
trying to convince you guys that um AI
is a structural bull market. uh which
you guys know that it is in my mind and
that the compute side uh there's
insatiable demand and it will be that
way
for a long time. But there's some things
that I've written about and talked about
um not just in terms of the AI midcycle
slowdown but also on market structure. I
wrote a piece in December on it. Uh, and
then I did a video on it that you guys
probably remember that wasn't too long
ago,
which is basically this. And the reason
I wanted to bring this up now is because
I wrote this in the middle of May. It's
when I really started to talk about the
fact that we had finally reached a peak,
a a peak in terms of it was obvious that
whether it was Korea or whether it was
the fact that every single person that I
talked to who I couldn't convince to buy
memory last year was now pushing back on
anything I was writing about in terms of
the fact that there'd be bottlenecks and
there'd be issues and the bar is now so
high. And then eventually it led to the
midcycle slowdown which was all about
the second derivative. But this thing
was on the market structure. And the
reason I want to talk about it now is
because this is only going to get worse.
So bubbles, parabas, and speed crashes.
Um we've seen the bubble in the form of
a parabola. And now we've absolutely
seen a speed crash in certain names with
inside AI. And in my opinion, this is
something that everyone's gonna have to
get used to, which is these parabolic
moves higher where everyone goes in
because momentum and buying what's
working is now being driven more than
ever by AI agents, which will only
increase and that their job is to be
non-emotional and to keep sourcing for
the best outcome. And momentum
historically is a good way to go. But
the problem is when you have leverage on
top of it, you end up getting this
scenario where V control kicks in. And
I'm going to get into that, but I just
want you to read this last line. Markets
are moving from manious panics and
crashes, which is the book by Charles
Kend Kindleberger to bubbles, parabas,
and speed crashes, faster up, faster
down, and structurally different. So
this is not a business cycle thing. So,
I'm starting [clears throat] to hear
people talk about the fact that, oh,
this is going to take down everything.
This is related to the AI debt
situation.
Basically, we went too high and we
needed to have a correction. And the way
that you know it is to look at this. So,
by now you guys have seen me either
[clears throat] in the subscriber
webinar this week posting on X. This is
the Morgan Stanley tech momentum factor
index. And this is the 18day rate of
change at minus40%.
Now they have data on this published in
Bloomberg back to 1998.
So this is by far by far the worst
unwind we have seen in tech mo momentum
momentum. So the tech momentum uh factor
down 40% in 18 days which takes us back
to June. I've shown this megaphone chart
now for a while and this is an
indication of how long this has been
building. So even though uh this may
look like it's been going since here,
the reality is this point here was still
in line with everything and this is opus
4.5. This is the agentic side. This is
what I've been writing about. This has
been what everyone has come back on
because the earnings have come through.
So this is the agentic trade which
brought more and more people into it and
V started to move higher really from
October. Now here is the momentum side.
This is not just the tech side which is
the uh the white line. The one that's
actually given up the most is the
industrial momentum which again is the
other factor I've highlighted on the
momentum side that is basically the AI
trade. Now this is overlaid with my
thematic portfolio. You can't separate
the correlation. You can't separate this
as time has gone on. MO is a chameleon.
It basically takes what's working and
what obviously has been working really
since October into November. November is
when Opus 4.5 was released. Everything
started to jump in and we got this
agentic movement and correlations with
inside my portfolio were close to one.
I wrote this paper on June 4th. The
firework show is over. Agentic AI moves
from discovery to digestion.
That is where I think we are in AI. The
firework show is over and the last
couple of weeks have been the climax and
an incredible display. But the agentic
AI buildout has just begun. So I wrote
about this. I'm not surprised by
anything that's happened. The fact that
we've had a correction that has given
back now more than 38%
about 40% of the move from Opus 4.5 is
not surprising to me. Some names are
down much more than that. I'll go
through some of those.
But it was this thing of more people are
now fighting against the bottleneck and
short side than against the agentic AI
buildout itself. For me, that usually
means that the all you can eat AI buffet
has left everyone full and in need of a
digestion period. So this was June 4th.
We've clearly gone through a digestion
period where we are eradicating the most
levered funds and people.
You guys can read the other highlighted
part. I just want to do this. As my
father taught me, the odds on the tote
board are now fair. So let's sit out
this race until we see better odds. We
have better odds right now. I have been
doing little buys on this week
particularly in the last two days. Uh I
even bought Micron at higher levels than
the average price of where I got out. I
did buy some slightly lower than where I
sold at my highest price. But the reason
I'm buying it is because since I sold
out and basically got rid of my last
share, which was in early June around
this paper,
there's been new news. So, I just want
you guys to go through because it is now
equally possible for companies to
underwhelm as it is for them to
overwhelm. A company can report
extraordinary growth, Micron, Samsung,
ASML, and still disappoint. Stock trades
lower. None of this is a surprise to me
that we're seeing a correction. If it
extends much further than here, yes, it
will be a correction. If it gets to the
50 day 50% retracement and then
immediately turns starts to turn back
up, it won't surprise me. Uh but as I've
said and I said on the webinar uh for
the subscribers this week, I don't
expect there to be a massive just bounce
out of here. And I'll get through the
reasons why. Um but remember the reason
this is held in bid better than the
single names. This has a hundred names
in it. They were chosen for a reason.
They were chosen because more diversity
on this is going to be better. I will be
making adjustments to the portfolio on
some of the names because there's been
new news over the last two months and
the price movements have basically
argued that they shouldn't be involved
in this even though they're going to
benefit. They will be disrupted sooner
than what people think. On the flip
side, I will be releasing this week the
paper on the 800 volt DC, the Vera Rubin
side, which will be a step up step up
function for some companies and that's
what the paper was about. Now, here is
the theatic portfolio showing it's
having no impact right now on the S&P
500 and yes, uh the equal weight S&P.
Now, this was uh through the early
morning on Friday, but we didn't have
that big of a move, but the S&P did
finish lower. But regardless, as this
unwind has happened so far, nothing has
gone on. And the major reason why is we
are now 43 names into the S&P 500
earnings period.
Look at the earnings surprise. We're
repeating what happened last quarter.
The sales surprise 4%. Earning surprise
16%. Already we're off to a huge start
on the earning side. And in particular
when you go through and you look at
these and I'm going to move head over. I
highlighted just here JP Morgan surprise
34% and the stock traded up 10%. I went
back and looked over history. You can't
find a time where JP Morgan traded up
10% on an earnings surprise where it was
trading near all-time highs. Goldman
Sachs beat by 45%. You can go through
all of these numbers. UNH, a dead
company. I've talked about the insurers.
Morgan Stanley 18%.
JB Hunt
10%. We're just getting beats again and
GDP is much stronger than even the data
suggests, especially from an earnings
basis. So, here are some quotes from
Jamie Diamond. It's getting as it's
getting close to as good as it gets. So,
let's go back and use a bare argument.
Well, I've seen that before. That
happens. Guys, don't let people go
through it. If the S&P is going down, it
wouldn't be up this much year-over-year.
So in every time in history that I have
gone through markets, the best recession
signal, which is what sometimes does
happen when you see a lot of statements
like that, the S&P year-over-year turns
negative. We're not even in the ballpark
of that happening anytime soon. We'd
have to fall significantly bounce. It
would take a while. I've given you guys
this stuff over time. Use the S&P 500 as
the best benchmark for the economy. Stan
Ducker Miller says it. All the models I
built that was the number one factor
involved with building it. The firm sees
conditions across consumer banking,
credit cards, commercial lending,
investment banking, trading, payments,
asset management, wealth man. The
strength is not confined to one narrow
corner.
Basically, the good as it gets is that
it's across the board. Now, if you go
into David Solomon's side,
everything is a similar comment except
their business is obviously more heavily
heavy uh heavily weighted towards the
investment banking side. But again, you
see all of them booming. The buildout of
AI infrastructure remains in its early
stages, and they're one of the companies
involved with selling the debt and
everything. This is not going to stop.
AI acting as a new structural engine
beneath that activity.
The AI infrastructure and investment
cycle is still early enough to support
years of financing, M&A, and capital
formation with inevitable bumps along
the way.
Goldman Sachs jumps to all-time high. JP
Morgan jumps to all-time high. Junk
spreads sit near all-time tights. And
this story goes around and I got asked
about it at least 10 times this week.
No worries for me whatsoever about this.
Zero Hedge does a good job of freaking
you people out. That's great. Everyone
sends me stuff going through isn't this
a worry as I go through it. Debt to
equity on these companies is next to
nothing. And as I've said repeatedly,
the hyperscalers, and this does not
include Open AI, and this does not
include Anthropic. If you guys want to
think that they're going to fall apart,
great. Except they're going to be
protected by the government. So, I
really don't know why you guys are
getting all excited about the the
leading model companies in the US when
we're race against China. But if you
want to go look at these again, the debt
to equity these companies is next to
nothing. And the combined RPOS,
contractual orders that they already
have where the reason they can't fill
them is because they don't have enough
compute. What is the debt for? To make
sure they have enough compute. The
compute demand is insatiable. Don't
listen to anything you hear from people
that argue otherwise. It is insatiable.
Insatiable. We will not be there anytime
in the next four years where we have
enough compute for all the intelligence
in the billions of agents that are
coming. The deleveraging factor. These
are just some of the prime uh the prime
book. Uh you can see the numbers. We are
taking these numbers down significantly
in some cases back below the levels of
26. Uh this was through the prior week.
So this is through January 10th. We had
already taken memory down significantly
in the long short side.
Yet another quant tremor strikes
systematic investors. Hedge funds that
rely on sophisticated modeling and
systematic trading have been rattled by
a series of mini crisis and insiders
have been mildly I've talked about this
on this video. It does feel a lot like
07 to me except for one problem. Spreads
are not widening and there is no
recession on the horizon. So if you guys
want to believe that there is, I had a
recession signal in Octo in September of
'07. That's because the S&P 500 went
negative year-over-year in September of
'07.
Also, claims were widening. There's a
whole bunch of other things that were
going on. Cuh profit margins had already
come down. There were a lot of issues
that were happening back in in ' 07. So,
I don't want you guys to look at this
and think this is another sign. Quad
funds just suffered their most crippling
trading route this year. That was as of
June 30th. We've had obviously far worse
things since then. AI selloff drives
quant funds worst performance since
August. Now, this is as of July 9th.
This is one of the issues that I want to
make sure people realize when I talk
about the human structure is over. Every
day more and more agents are responsible
for trading activity because Robin Hood
as of the end of May
is open to agents so people could do it.
Strategies that work harder so you don't
have to. So we I've always said we are
heading towards a bubble of optimized
portfolios where people are mistakenly
believing that their risk control is
tighter than what it is. Sharp ratios
will come down for exactly what we've
seen. We have seen an unprecedented rise
in factor VA that has never been seen
before in history. This goes way back in
terms of that tech momentum side and
what the VA is. I do not think this is
coming back anytime soon. And I'll go
back. And when I say anytime soon, I
think we're going to have much higher
volal scenarios that were hundred-year
storms. They're going to happen all the
time because things are going to get
more crowded than they used to and the
liquidity is going to be one direction.
it's going to be the right risk, but it
will unwind and then it will take a
while to set back in. Um, and I think
that's where we are in the AI trade
right now. Uh, the B of the Bank of
England warned about this AI agents risk
causing market meltdowns.
So, again, here it is 39 40% for the
something that hasn't happened before,
but it has happened before in other
assets. So, gold at the beginning of
this year, this is a three-day move in
gold. the biggest in 35 years. Silver
[clears throat] had a 40% fall in five
days. So, it's not like we haven't seen
these things. And these were with big
momentum trades. So, you know what this
is starting to look like.
Bitcoin gets 40% drawd downs in 18 days.
This is my point about what is happening
in the world as everything gets
tokenized. And for those of you who have
not yet
done your homework on crypto, you will
be paying a price in my opinion very
very soon. This is getting much much
harder for people to
it seems like understand, but we're
going to be in that position. So, you're
going to need to pay attention to crypto
and especially as I get through the end
of this and I start to take you through.
But consumer agents, the rise of agents
leads to more crypto.
Bitcoin is the collateral of the future.
I'll be writing about it and as I do my
new YouTube, for those of you who are
already in crypto, you're starting to
reach out. For you hedge fund people,
mutual fund people, this is going to be
where the beta is over the next 12
months. Uh it's not going to be joining
back into the infrastructure trade. Even
though it'll outperform, I just don't
see this happening. This is going to be
consumer agent thing. So, it's going to
be more idiosyncratic with names, but
that's going to be very dangerous as
we're going to see over the course of
the next month. There's going to be a
lot of names that are disrupted by AI
with AI agents. Here's the gold
situation, and this is where this gets
important. So, this is the 60-day V,
which went up to a record, except for
here, and I'll show you why this
actually was a record, especially when
you're dealing with optimized
portfolios. Here was silver again,
60-day V back 35 years. Here's
techvall the the tech moval which is now
at 92
has not stopped today was a quiet day
because we rallied back but to look at
S&P V down here not moving so if you had
a portfolio and this was one asset and
this was the other and you were VA
waiting them now it's very hard for this
thing which is according to this seven
times as volatile so what should your
appropriate position if you're equal
risk weight be it's going to be very
hard for leverage funds to go back into
this regardless of whether it's a pod
regardless of whether it's a systematic
strategy or anything else that is vault
controlled like Korean retail it's going
to be very difficult to get back in
because the margins are going to be
higher now here is gold and silver this
is silver this is gold and what you'll
notice is these things did this while
the S&P V did not rise during the times
that we had high V in these things. The
S&P V was also high. This is what's
changing in the marketplace. And for me,
it's going to stay this way forever. As
we get into tokenization, as we get into
24 hours a day, I believe that
everything will trade differently and
that you will be in a situation that
this that the the structure, the market
structure is going to forever change. In
my opinion, it is much better for uh
allocators that can make decisions over
the long term, not have to deal with the
minutia of the day-to-day and these
little blips. Right now, if a mutual
fund was behind on putting money to work
in the AI trade, and now they've done
their homework, and they believe that
they should have more money in chips,
well, they're getting a correction back
to levels that make more sense. Uh, I
actually didn't show this chart. I I
just want to highlight that here's the
30-day V is even up here. So, when this
stuff starts to h to move down, what
you'll see is the 30-day will come down
obviously before the 60-day. We we're
not seeing that yet. Um this is again
the the V for the two one year on
on the tech side. So this is techmo
one-year vault which is 60 S&P vault one
of the lowest in history or at least in
the last 20 30 years.
Here's the chart of gold. So again that
V pickup was in here. It hasn't been
able to get anything there and it
actually is just tired. It's not that
this is going the V's coming down, it's
just tired. Um, and I think we're going
to see that in the same way silver.
We've seen it in Bitcoin as well. So,
here's where you have Adobe. The reason
I want to bring this up is all of the AI
stuff is going down, but it's going down
right now with the 200 day pointing up
for 85% of the names in my portfolio. So
we are way we were way above the 200
day. In the case of software which
unwound particularly this year the 200
day was already down. This is Adobe. If
you go to Salesforce you get the same
story. These are downward moving 200 day
moving averages. These stocks are toast.
They may bounce back up to the 200 day
but they're going to have to pivot their
business. And you're going to see this a
lot more. You're even going to see it
for the me the the semiconductor names
at some point over the next 10 years. I
just don't think it's happening for the
next three. So, if you ask me what to
watch for a bottom or why did I buy
Micron, well, I wrote this piece on June
29th basically saying
AI equals memory. And I'm going to keep
saying that AI equals memory. Now, here
are DRAM prices for basically
the three, four, and five. All of them
are going higher. So, even the three,
the green one here, the old one,
it doesn't stop. We have a shortage in
memory. These guys are doing long-term
contracts. Their earnings blew away.
Micron's earnings estimates were taking
up dramatically after I had taken out of
something that I had basically had an 8
to10 bagger on. And now it's more
confirmation based on everything that
I've heard, everything I've listened to
that consumer agents are coming within
the next 6 months. We have made more
progress in AI even over the last month.
Yet another model come out today in K uh
Kimmy K 3.0 which I can't use to replace
my Kimmy K 2.5 because I don't have
enough hardware. Um we are still in the
beginning stages. I'm going to show this
chart over and over again partly for
when you get worried about compute.
There will not ever we will not catch up
to this. We have exponential growth of
eating tokens which is what these
digital agents consume. They don't
consume houses. They don't consume
potato chips. They don't consume h uh
anything. They don't get paid. They get
paid in tokens. And the amount of tokens
they need will grow as they continue to
get smarter. Then consumer agents will
come in. So far we only have the
enterprise agents. Always remember that
chart if you ever start to get worried
until memory stops acting bad on good
news.
Go through it. But as I said last week,
I'm not really concerned about it. Um,
this chart's horrible. I mean, most
technicians are going to call for it to
come down here. Head and shoulders top.
No way it's going to stop till it gets
down here. I did see some technicians
that said, you know, their confidence
level is very high that we're going to
get back down to here. We might. I don't
think we will, but if we do, I don't
think it'll stay there. Today was the
first day we had a change in
a pattern that I'm I'm looking at. I'm
going to try to bring you guys some of
the nuances of how I grew up at Morgan
Stanley as a trader. I am an active tape
reader. I use a lot of intraday stuff.
This is the opening. So, when I traded
the S&P book, I would always use the
opening and close for a very, very
important signal, especially when it
comes to VWAPs. Um, and that's really
related to anything that's being sold
off to me on a risk basis, whether it's
a close out of a fund or whether it's a
systematic fund that's taking down
leverage. I believe it's going to be
taken out with much more activity on the
VWAP side. So, what I did here just for
today, um, this is a 60-minute chart and
I'm only looking at the opening to 10:30
for Micron. And what you'll see today is
two things I like. Number one, we got
back above
uh the VWOP very early on. And more
importantly, it was the biggest volume
first hour way above the average
since the peak since we were at 1300. So
that is a trend change at least
something that's going on.
I mentioned before I basically got out
of Micron in on early June. They
reported numbers
This is where their earnings for the
earnings estimates are for the pro the
next year. I knew they were going to
beat but the numbers were dramatic and
the contracts that they signed were a
game changer for them. So I am buying
it. One of the other reasons I'm buying
it is just because we got the correction
and I just want to show you guys
something in here. So Nvidia is a name
to look at and to let's assume that this
was 1300 in micron.
Nvidia was a 12bagger
over a period that's not too dissimilar
from Micron.
Then it comes down from that point
to where it is today, which is another
two years, you've made 48%. Not a bad
return. Over two years, you're getting
20 plus% compounded returns. A lot
better if you bought it into weakness
after this, which if let's assume that
I'm trying to buy something now down
here in this thing. Um but the main
point is number number one the 200week
moving average we never got to Nvidia's
had tremendously good earnings. So if
you just think Micron's going to go up
again in violent fashion even after the
earnings are great I don't see it
happening. The one big difference is the
multiple here of Micron was about six
times what it is right now on
Micron. So Nvidia's uh was much higher.
Here are the Nvidia earnings. So again,
that quarter in in June was kind of the
last
beat. That's when they peaked. So before
that, we were getting good reactions in
the stock. And then since then, the
price changes on the earnings, it
basically has gone down almost all the
time. I think we're probably in the the
midst of that right now. If you see a
change in that, it's good. All right,
back to the fireworks show again and the
fact that this is not something that was
surprising or shouldn't be and the fact
that we want to sit a race out here is
the other thing I've learned.
So the head and shoulders pattern that
we saw in Micron, the reason that I went
to Silicon Valley back in 2013, as I've
mentioned before, was because of Amazon
and because of something that's similar
to this. So Nvidia had a head and
shoulders pattern
in here back in 23 and I told you it
peaked in 24. So my gut tells me this is
where we are in micron right now. One of
my favorite charts to buy is a
structural bull market when you break a
neckline of a head and shoulders and
then you immediately go back up. Now we
haven't done that yet in Micron, but
that's what I'm looking for and that's
what I'd be interested in. Amazon. This
is the one that basically sent me to
Silicon Valley because once it traded up
again and we got through the Mario
Draghggy line in the sand and we made
new alltime highs in this again when
there were no earnings,
I had to go to Silicon Valley to
understand how this name could trade
like that. That every time there was a
head and shoulders pattern or some kind
of topping formation, when it broke
below, it would just go right back up.
If what I believe in AI is happening,
that's what you're going to end up
seeing in this. Here's Nvidia. It did
trade below the 200 day eventually, but
it took a long time after this peak. So,
I do think what's likely to happen is
something similar to this, but we could
be in here and we could still have
another race in Micron and then go
through this. It could be completely
different. I'm just giving you kind of
my perspective on the on what I've
learned about. So, let's go through the
recap for the week with all the news
going on. The S&P was down one and a
half%. Q's were down 4%.
small caps didn't budge
and we had this down this big. What this
tells me is 100% this is rotation. This
is factor unwinds. This is people
covering one thing and covering another
thing on the other side. Uh I don't see
this as anything systemic. And most
importantly, I've shown you the sector
momentum chart. This is all the sector
Morgan Stanley sector momentums. The
white line here is the index for
momentum
non- sectorbased. So this is just
momentum. Here are the two sectors that
I had shown before were way out of whack
and had to come back eventually. Well,
that's industrials and that's tech. And
it did that. Here are the other ones.
Some of them were up, some of them are
down. No movement. That's how I feel
confident that this is just a rotation.
The thematic portfolio bad week. Uh
luckily my risk is down significantly
from when it was in here and that's the
point of writing the papers in here and
going through it. I still have names and
one of them Marll is down sharply. Uh
that's my biggest uh one behind Eli Liy
at this point. But the index itself it's
getting a correction that right now is
right around 40%.
Um a fairly normal correction
particularly after a big move. Here's
Marll. Marll got down to 62%. It's been
painful. Um, but again, I made a lot of
money on the way up. I took some off.
It's still my biggest position. It's
really the only semi I own except for
Nvidia at this point, but a lot of the
other ones, Integris, um, Fluence, I
have small positions. Uh, Kimors, uh,
there's a lot of these names where I
have positions on, uh, they're all down.
So, and trust me, when I sold out of a
lot of this stuff, most a good portion
of the money that I rotated into was
into Bitcoin, Ethereum, and uh silver.
And those things haven't really bounced
that much. On a relative basis, they've
done very well relative to this, but
they're not bouncing much. Um, again,
thematic portfolio relative to equal
weight and relative to the S&P. This
includes today's data.
again not not having an impact on the
market at this point and I don't expect
it to because I don't think there's
anything behind this and you're going to
have to do this in the face of good
earnings and at some point good earnings
are going to matter for the broader
market and for some of these uh
infrastructure names. Here's the
correlation between the momentum factor
and my uh my thematic portfolio. This is
the Morgan Stanley one if you guys want
to trade it. You can see how well this
stuff has hung in there. So AI is
dragging lower. The thematic portfolio
is hanging in there better. Uh the
breath in the market made new all-time
highs this week. Equal weight basically
made new all it did make new all-time
highs this week.
Apple
one of the largest stocks in the world.
A consumer agent story. Talked about it
last week. Bad news, bad news. Boom.
Consumer agents are coming, guys. You
can play it through that way or you can
play it through crypto. Um, Philly Fed
and the Empire came out this week for
those of you wondering if there's any
weakness happening in the AI
infrastructure trade. So, this is a uh I
just combine the two, divide it by two,
and then I overlay it with the PMI. So,
you can see that we're basically at a 62
PMI equa uh uh uh level for those two.
So, we'll see what happens with the
other ones, but again, the economy is
strong and inflation is not. So, we got
inflation data this week. Uh, it was
much lower than expected. And here is
PCE core, the one that got every
economist to say there's three rate
hikes or two rate hikes or whatever
they're talking about before the end of
the year. Um, I talked about last week
that to me there was a decent chance
that July could be one if these numbers
came out above just by where the
percentage was and the fact that if you
really cared about Fed credibility, why
not get this out way before the midterms
and just do something to show it. But
you get these CPI prints which basically
take the white line here which is the
sticky core 12 month from the Atlanta
Fed to new lows. You have true flation
at new lows. You have core CPI turned
down. You have the trim mean, the one he
prefers. It's only one number. And
again, I think people read him wrong.
I'm not the only one. Here's what the
swap market did this week with oil
backing up and bombings going
everywhere. Didn't budge, guys.
Here are the expectations from the
Cleveland Fed now casting. They got last
month kind of right. They were minus.2.
It came in at minus.4.
Uh for July, we're now, you know, we're
17 days through. We're through the
midpoint. Uh minus again they have with
the headline going down to 3.3.
Morgan Stanley put this out and I talked
about this last week. I completely
agree. Worsh is all about reform, not
hawkishness. I think people are just
reading him wrong on everything he's
doing in this. I believe the reform
thing is really important and I showed
the the quotes from him in both an
interview uh in Europe but also in the
testimony in front of Congress. Well,
here he is testifying again and he goes
through this stuff again and he talks
about AI will raise prices but don't
call it inflation. Um, Worsh is
rhetorically hawkish about the inflation
outcome, but intellectually reformist,
understands the economy. Again, he's a
market practitioner, and I really do
believe that the most important thing is
to ignore the backward-looking data and
to focus with a heavier weight on the
forward-looking data. We've seen this in
every part of AI. If you believe an
exponential move, which is happening, if
you believe in AGI sitting in front of
us, which I'll get into, it would be a
huge mistake for a central banker to be
making decisions based on one month's
data, the past. I want to fight
inflation and get it back down. That is
old school stuff when you're staring at
something this powerful. And this is
what you need to go read. Deis Sabis
I've talked about on here is by far of
the people at the large companies the
one that I think is the most honest. I
think he has been the one that has been
around the longest in terms of talking
about AGI. Deep mind his first comments
on AGI were back in 2010 and he said it
would happen around 2030.
This is a pivotable this is him writing
this. This is a pivotal moment in human
history. The artificial general
intelligence, a system that exhibits all
the cognitive capabilities the brain
has, is probably only a few short years
away. When we look back on this time in
the decades to come, think Kevin Worsh,
I think we will realize we were standing
in the foothills of the singularity,
nothing less than the dawning of a new
age for humanity.
Whatever why whatever reason you guys
watch my video each week, I spend so
much time on this and it began in 2013
when I went to Silicon Valley and I went
to Singularity University. I believed in
this because it was pure math. We're
going to be there in a few years by
someone who is honest is at one of the
forefronts and arguably the best place
for figuring out when this is going to
happen. And I would say better than
Dario Modi and better than Sam Alman.
And this guy doesn't run the company.
Sundar does. So he wrote this because
there are so many things in this that
are critical.
The writing portrays AGI as a
civilizational transformation rather
than normal technological innovation
that may arrive within only a few years.
It could be comparable to the discovery
of fire or electricity because it would
expand our ability to think, invent, and
solve problems across every field.
Accelerate drug discovery, clean energy,
advanced materials, productivity, and
scientific progress. Humanity may be
standing at the beginning of a new age.
You read all of this and go through it,
the world is going to change more than
you can possibly imagine. This is an
important piece from Demis. We need more
kind of this thinking. A good reminder
that the goal is a frontier ecosystem
that promotes innovation and choice
while avoiding anyone model drop that
breaks the world. Again, this is
worrying about this. Sasha has has has a
bias on this, but I just think that this
traveled through it got a lot of reads.
It's really important. I highly
recommend when you start thinking about
oh the economy is going to humanoids are
coming in three years like we're going
to be flying all over the place we are
raising our capbacks this is Morgan
Stanley I just want to highlight the
fact that in weeks where people are
saying that there's not going to be
capbacks there won't be buildouts we
still have it or oh another openweight
model that stuns the frontier model this
must be the end of anthropic no it's not
uh if you guys want to hear my
viewpoints on this. Listen to Pomp this
week. Um I talked about it. We got into
a very long discussion about model
router model routers. In the end, open
source will be dominating most
enterprises, just not in the near term.
Um they're still in the stage of
figuring this out. Where it will
dominate is AI native companies and AI
native companies will win. Public
companies will lose. I've talked about
this before. I've been very brash with
people in saying that I think in 2030 I
don't know if we're going to know any
company that will have a three-year
horizon where they're guaranteed to be
around physical companies by then if we
have AGI and Demis is right they'll be
solving so many science there'll be so
many breakthroughs
I I don't know what to say we can solve
problems we had a solution on uh on
software this week for semiconductors
like everything is going to happen guys
it's just a question of when this is the
Ruben piece. I spent a lot of time on
this. It took me six weeks to put
together. There's about 25 names which
are not in my thematic portfolio. Some
of these will probably go into it just
because there's a lot of different
companies. Uh there are a lot of Asian
companies that are in this as well. Uh
you've you've seen some of them. The
chart the chart's not going to be much
different than the thematic portfolio at
least the way it was so far. But I do
think as Vera Rubin rolls out, a lot of
these companies are going to see a step
up function. And that's the way I did
the report. I'm looking for step-up
functions from their earnings. So now
let's finish it off with crypto. So
Bitcoin
just kind of hanging around here. Still
in a bare market, gets above the 20-day,
stays above it all week, breaks above
the 50-day, sells back down to it. Uh
it isn't out of the woods yet. I
wouldn't say there's no chance of it
breaking to new lows, but it is what it
is. Ethereum, well, another little mini
break. You like to see these. You got
the 20-day above 50-day. You took out a
trend line break here. Ethereum's
hanging in. And as I've said before, and
I'll show you why, Ethereum is the one
to watch.
And on that front, in the face of
momentum, of which crypto is usually
very correlated to equity momentum,
particularly tech momentum,
in a very quiet fashion, which I love,
Ethereum is having its best month, up
17% monthto date since August of last
year.
Think about that.
Here's the ratio with Bitcoin also
having its best month. So this is the
cross, Ethereum over Bitcoin. If we are
in what I think we are, which is an
agent revolution, then Ethereum should
be benefiting more than Bitcoin at this
part. Here's the chart of that. Again,
this looks a lot better than the chart
of each name individually. And I love
the like the yuing situation. So, if we
can get above the 200 day on this, I
think it sends a very good message. Now
driving this in terms of looking at
things here is the correlation between
Bitcoin and momentum that I talked
about. So this is back through November.
So this is basically tw 12 December of
23 the end of the year. So this is about
two years worth of data. That's how
correlated it was. So the fact that
these are acting good is a good sign.
Here's another good sign. Stripe put in
a bid for PayPal.
I did a video on Stripe acquiring Bridge
back in 2024.
So, this was October of 24 when I did
this. If you guys haven't seen it and
you want to catch up,
Stripe acquired Stablecoin
infrastructure from Bridge for 1.1
billion. And now they're looking into
PayPal. And this is a stable coin story.
So I put this together and basically
highlighted that
PayPal is in my 40name crypto thematic
index which again I will put out for
subscribers to see in September or
October. It will not be before
September, October. It will be late
September, early October somewhere in
there. I'm spending a lot of time on
this guys. Um, I think it's important
for you guys to spend the time on on
this part, but what I highlighted was
this chart. So, this is the 40name index
and this is year-to date. So, Bitcoin
hanging in there.
This as and this is before the close of
of yesterday or two days ago. So, on
Thursday, the day of the PayPal, but I
put this in I posted this in X. This is
what I want to see. So just like
Ethereum is outperforming, the 40name
index is outperforming. I believe the
ecosystem of of crypto is already
growing in a very big way in front of
people.
JP Morgan, Black Rockck, and Goldman
tokenized stocks and treasuries. That
was this week. All of this stuff is
starting. Oh, Bitcoin banking adoption
hits 32% average as major banks and
financial institutions integrate.
the value of tokenized real world
assets. The chart is
it is going up higher and higher.
Prediction markets, open interest
continues to grow. All of this is
blockchain related stuff. Sorry you
can't see this. I screwed up putting
this presentation together. It happens.
But basically the revenues in here are
large. These are a variety of companies.
You obviously have Hyperlquid which is
involved in the private markets. So the
tokenized situation, but you know
wherethropic and open AAI and different
places. You've also got I can't remember
all the ones here. Pancake pancakes uh
swap. You've got a bunch of others. The
main thing is the revenues are coming in
because there's activity happening in
the ecosystem. Why the clarity act
matters for crypto consumers.
This is why it matters. Consumer agents,
guys, this is a big deal that is going
to happen. and if the Clarity Act can
get done, of which it's now back up to a
40% chance below 50, but we'll see what
happens. I it's important for the United
States to get it done. [clears throat] I
don't think it's that important for
crypto in general, except for maybe a
knee-jerk. I do believe that the agents
are the most important thing, and that's
what's going to happen across the globe.
It was a big week. Japan's landmark vote
reclassifies Bitcoin and crypto as
financial assets. That was in Japan this
week. in South Korea writes crypto into
state asset rulebook after 76 years.
South Korea moves to allow spot Bitcoin
ETFs.
And here's the most important thing I
can show you. The VA is nowhere. So, I'm
going to say this again if I'm right
that the ecosystem of crypto is in the
early stages. It's in the purest AI
trade where it cannot be disrupted from
AI because it's built on scarcity and
there is no competition for it. It's
like gold in the fact that it is
survived the test of time. So it has a
moat. Religion has a moat. Gold has a
moat. Bitcoin has a moat.
If this is the time, it will start with
this here. So if you break the 200 day
moving average, I believe most people,
if not all, will be heavily involved in
crypto over the next 12 months. I don't
think we're going to necessarily break
through the 200 day moving average
before uh let's say October, November. I
think this is a second half of the or
fourth quarter story, but if it does
happen, guys, just be ready. Um, get
ready for my uh work that I'm on there
and you guys will get to see it. Until
then, have a good week, guys. I'll see
you next week and we'll look for bottoms
and if anything important happens during
the week, I will do a subscriber video.
So, uh, look there and be on top of it.
See you.